<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conservation on LEARNING FROM APES</title>
    <link>/tags/conservation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conservation on LEARNING FROM APES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/conservation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Charming Yunnan Youth Publicity Team of Popular Sciences (CYYTPS)</title>
      <link>/project/cyytps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cyytps/</guid>
      <description>Our publicity of popular science work got started in 2014. All of us are younger and lack of experience. The beginning is not easy, we were nervous during the lectures. Even our work is public welfare, not every one accepted us. We insist for several years, keep learning from outside, and adopt variety of forms to conduct publicity. We have maintained our enthusiasm for this work. It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to start writing about our research, and it is happy to tell people in simple words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoolock gibbon conservation in Yunnan, China</title>
      <link>/project/tianxinggibbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tianxinggibbon/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, we conducted the hoolock gibbon hoolock tianxing survey in Yingjiang County. The survey reported the hoolock gibbon population status and the impacts of anthropogenic activities on the species in Yingjiang County, West Yunnan, China. The survey was undertaken from January to December 2015, Dr. Guan Zhenhua and Associate Professor Li Maobiao from Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Southwest Forestry University and supported by the Gibbon Conservation Alliance. To assess the anthropogenic threats to hoolock gibbon Hoolock tianxing populations and potential conservation measures, we choose 14 relevant communities in two townships to conduct interview and transect survey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>