<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LEARNING FROM APES on LEARNING FROM APES</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LEARNING FROM APES on LEARNING FROM APES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My research work</title>
      <link>/project/researchwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/researchwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research work focus on gibbon behavioral ecology and conservation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charming Yunnan Youth Publicity Team of Popular Sciences (CYYTPS)</title>
      <link>/project/cyytps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cyytps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/teamer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I am talking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our publicity of popular science work got started in 2014. All of us are younger and lack of experience. The beginning is not easy, we were nervous during the lectures. Even our work is public welfare, not every one accepted us. We insist for several years, keep learning from outside, and adopt variety of forms to conduct publicity. We have maintained our enthusiasm for this work. It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to start writing about our research, and it is happy to tell people in simple words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/students.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I am talking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The primate in forests</title>
      <link>/talk/yabteamtalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/yabteamtalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is opening ceremony with the first speech. I gave the speech on the topic &amp;ldquo;The apes and monkeys in Yunnan&amp;rdquo;. In this speech, I talk about primates on the earth. Specifically, I talk leave monkeys and gibbons in Yunnan. All the junior school students showed their passion and curiosity on my topic. Start with the figure &amp;ldquo;King of monkey&amp;rdquo;, end with how we conduct research on them, and why they need conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/talking1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1000px&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/talking2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I am talking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scraping data from wiki to analyze olympic medal</title>
      <link>/post/scraping-data-from-wiki-to-analyze-olympic-medal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scraping-data-from-wiki-to-analyze-olympic-medal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I learn Edwin Thoen from R-blogger. The topic is how to scrape the data from wikepedia and tidy the data in a format in which they can be analyzed. Thank Edwin for sharing the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrape data from website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;code&gt;rvest&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tidy&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)
library(tidyverse)
library(stringr)
Olympics_2018_wiki &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_2018_Winter_Olympics_medal_winners&amp;quot;)
sports &amp;lt;- html_nodes(Olympics_2018_wiki, &amp;quot;h2&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% html_text()
sports %&amp;gt;% head(3)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;Alpine skiing[edit]&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Biathlon[edit]&amp;quot;      &amp;quot;Bobsleigh[edit]&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;html_text&lt;/code&gt; is used to convert the &lt;code&gt;xml&lt;/code&gt; nodes to regular R characters. I get 18 strings, first 15 elements contain the sport’s names with “edit”, next step is to remove “edit” parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sports &amp;lt;- 
  sports %&amp;gt;% 
  `[`(1:15) %&amp;gt;% 
  str_split(&amp;quot;\\[&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% 
  map_chr(1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above [ is used ad prefix function for subsetting, rather than its usual usage object[index]. &lt;code&gt;purrr::map_chr&lt;/code&gt; will select the first element of each vector and store the result in a single character vector. This part get the olympic event name list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;medals &amp;lt;- html_nodes(Olympics_2018_wiki, &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  html_table() %&amp;gt;% 
  `[`(3:26)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reasons I checked manually that the 3rd up until the 26th table contain the results. Now, if you visit the wiki page you will notice that some sports have a single results table (such as Curling), while others have several (for women’s, for men’s, and some even for mixed events). I counted on the website the number of tables for each sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tables_by_sport &amp;lt;- c(3, 3, 1, 2, 1, 1, 2, 1, 1, 1, 2, 1, 1, 2, 2)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I want to tell about my research</title>
      <link>/post/what-i-want-to-tell-about-my-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/what-i-want-to-tell-about-my-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About primates, what do I want to tell the others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is about biodiversity, evolution, and human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, the gibbon is only one of the five hundreds of primate species, and the primates are only five hundreds of the ten millions of animal species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Yunnan, most primates dwelled on forests. So all the stories can not happen without refering to forests. In case of we seeing a monkey or gibbon move in tree canopy, we want to know where they are going and what they are going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the answers to these questions are difficult to get, we have to use some techniques and pay much efforts. From the simplest to the most difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the begining, I was thinking if I can catch one, and ask him the questions. Of course it is not true, even I catch one, the monkey does not speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I have to do is doing research in scientific way, and resolve the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Where are you going?” To answer this question, I have to follow the gibbon group for all days. Then I find out, they are heading to valley to forage ripe fruits; they are going to mountain ridge to bathe in the sun；they are going to patrol the habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?” To answer the question, I have to observe them. Then I find out, they are foraging specific nutrient, such as protein; they sing every day for inter-group communication; they choose a proper and flat canopy for playing, which are important activity during their development stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For year and year, the answers reveal their adaptation to forest living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why they exist, like all the lives, for inheritance of gene, mutation and their culture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge to graph using same y axis</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In case of that I want to plot several graphs, and the datasets are same and variables are same. How to make it in a compact way, such as I want them share the same y-axis and distinct x-axis, or verse visa. Or I treat X variables in different ways, log and 1/x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use code from stackexchange.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(&amp;quot;PtProcess&amp;quot;)
lambda &amp;lt;- 1.5
a &amp;lt;- 1
pareto &amp;lt;- rpareto(1000,lambda=lambda,a=a)
x_pareto &amp;lt;- seq(from=min(pareto),to=max(pareto),length=1000)
y_pareto &amp;lt;- 1-ppareto(x_pareto,lambda,a)
df1 &amp;lt;- data.frame(x=x_pareto,cdf=y_pareto)

library(ggplot2)
library(gridExtra)
g1 &amp;lt;- ggplot(df1,aes(x=x,y=cdf)) + geom_line() + scale_x_log10()+ ylim(0,1.2)+  theme(plot.margin = unit(c(0,-.5,0,.5), &amp;quot;lines&amp;quot;),
            plot.background = element_blank()) +
      ggtitle(&amp;quot;pareto&amp;quot;)


mean &amp;lt;- 3
norm &amp;lt;- rnorm(1000,mean=mean)
x_norm &amp;lt;- seq(from=min(norm),to=max(norm),length=1000)
y_norm &amp;lt;- pnorm(x_norm,mean=mean)
df2 &amp;lt;- data.frame(x=x_norm,cdf=y_norm)

g2 &amp;lt;- ggplot(df2,aes(x=x,y=cdf)) + geom_line()+ ylim(0,1.2)+
  theme(axis.text.y = element_blank(), 
            axis.ticks.y = element_blank(), 
            axis.title.y = element_blank(),
            plot.margin = unit(c(0,1,0,-1), &amp;quot;lines&amp;quot;),
            plot.background = element_blank()) +
      ggtitle(&amp;quot;norm&amp;quot;)
grid.arrange(g1, g2, ncol=2)  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-03-16-how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;next is the graph using ggplotGrob&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;G1 &amp;lt;- ggplotGrob(g1)
G2 &amp;lt;- ggplotGrob(g2)

grid.arrange(G1, G2, ncol=2)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-03-16-how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not exactly, but step forward. Finally, I use &lt;code&gt;grid&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(grid)
grid.newpage()
grid.draw(cbind(ggplotGrob(g1), ggplotGrob(g2),size = &amp;quot;last&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-03-16-how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-3-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# library(gridExtra)
# g &amp;lt;- arrangeGrob(g1, g2,nrow=1) 
# plot(g)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great work!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoolock gibbon conservation in Yunnan, China</title>
      <link>/project/tianxinggibbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tianxinggibbon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2015gibbonsurvey1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Interview&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, we conducted the hoolock gibbon &lt;em&gt;hoolock tianxing&lt;/em&gt; survey in Yingjiang County. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gibbonconservation.org/index_engl.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey reported&lt;/a&gt; the hoolock gibbon population status and the impacts of anthropogenic activities on the species in Yingjiang County, West Yunnan, China. The survey was undertaken from January to December 2015, Dr. Guan Zhenhua and Associate Professor Li Maobiao from Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Southwest Forestry University and supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gibbonconservation.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gibbon Conservation Alliance&lt;/a&gt;. To assess the anthropogenic threats to hoolock gibbon &lt;em&gt;Hoolock tianxing&lt;/em&gt; populations and potential conservation measures, we choose 14 relevant communities in two townships to conduct interview and transect survey. There are 18 groups in Yingjiang County, of which 14 groups are distributed in the collective forests outside the existing nature reserve, which are under local community management. Few direct threats to gibbon were found. The main threats are fructus tsaokos expansion leading to forest fragmentation, and the multiple groups may already been genetically isolated. To address this issue we recommend a series of conservation actions that should be implemented in the near future. We suggest to cooperate with the local forestry bureaus to investigate the land/forest tenures of all the gibbon habitat areas as this has great impacts on the conservation project designing and development in Yingjiang County. Meanwhile, scientific research should be conducted on some groups for providing an underlying foundation for hoolock gibbon conservation. Through some type of community-based conservation education program, we recommend habitat-friendly fructus tsaoko cultivation, for instance, leaving or planting more large trees and food sources trees in the fructus tsaoko fields. For the long-term conservation of gibbons, we consider that the initial habitat restoration efforts should be conducted to connect the subpopulations in Lamahe and Xiangbai.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hawking</title>
      <link>/post/rememberinghawking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rememberinghawking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man’s greatness lies in his power of thought. —— Blaise Pascal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;思想形成人的伟大。人只不过是一根卢伟，是自然界最脆弱的东西；但他是一根会思想的苇草。用不着整个宇宙都拿起武器来才能毁灭他；一口气、一滴水就足以致他死命了。然而，纵使宇宙毁灭了他，人却仍然要比致他于死命的东西更高贵许多；因为他知道自己要死亡，以及宇宙对他所具有的优势，而宇宙对此却是一无所知。 —— 帕斯卡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step to Student Opening Report</title>
      <link>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/htmlwidgets/htmlwidgets.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/viz/viz.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/DiagrammeR-styles/styles.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/grViz-binding/grViz.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I do some student work, including secretary working for opening report defencing. So I use grViz to make a step graph for the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34; style=&#34;width:672px;height:480px;&#34; class=&#34;grViz html-widget&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/json&#34; data-for=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34;&gt;{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;diagram&#34;:&#34;\ndigraph boxes_and_circles {\n\n  # a \&#34;graph\&#34; statement\n  graph [overlap = true, fontsize = 10]\n\n  # several \&#34;node\&#34; statements\n  node [shape = box,\n        fontname = Helvetica, color=OrangeRed]\n  a [label = \&#34;Defence Secretary\&#34;];\n  b [label = \&#34;Defence Chairman\&#34;];\n  c [label = \&#34;Teaching Secretary\&#34;]; \n  d [label = \&#34;All the students\&#34;]; \n  e [label = \&#34;All the teachers\&#34;] \n\n  # several \&#34;edge\&#34; statements\n  a -&gt; b [label = \&#34;determine the name list of student\&#34;, arrowhead = diamond]\n  a -&gt; c [label = \&#34;determine the date and classroom\&#34;, arrowhead = diamond]\n  c -&gt; e [arrowhead = diamond]\n  d -&gt; e [arrowhead = diamond]\n  a -&gt; d [label = \&#34;collect all the opening reports\&#34;, arrowhead = diamond]\n  a -&gt; e [label = \&#34;opening report defence with students\&#34;, arrowhead = diamond]\n}\n&#34;,&#34;config&#34;:{&#34;engine&#34;:&#34;dot&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:null}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks awful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the defencing, I find almost all the students do not understand what they are going to do. Basically, all the students just follow the teachers’ command, and not think by themselves, therefore, they fail to grab the core of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A opening defence for one student is limited in 5 minutes, so essentially if one student fail to grab the core, he does success in no way. It is not the matter whether the question is difficult, it is effort payed by the student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a simple way, for 5 minutes defence, one student have to answer several questions to himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do I want to tell my teacher? What is my research point? It is easy to suicide by telling the studying history. For example, I study time budget of primate in the opening period, my research point is the time budget. So I want to tell the teachers I want to study primate time budget for three reasons, the first is to understand how the primates adapt to the specific habitats; The second is to understand how the different individuals adjust their time budget to group living, or the difference among individuals varies in ages, breeding status, sex and social positions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second step is to explain how I study. I use instantaneous scanning sample method with 5-minute interval, and I collect the behavioral data for 5 months, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is the conclusion. For university student, any conclusion from the experiment is acceptable. Such as I find difference among individuals at different ages, which implies the development affect the time budget. Or sex, or breeding status, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three steps way is not a trick, but a refining from the work. 5 minutes is enough for a university students work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the defence meeting, several problems were exposed. Of course it is good for correction in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The first thing is almost all the students could not understand the aims of their research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 All the students only know a little about their research, they can not answer the quesitons from review teachers, some questions are little further from the research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 All the students did not prepare or train for the defence meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation Project</title>
      <link>/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrients for nonhuman primate</title>
      <link>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Protein is important for primates, because it is the vital source for amino acids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about strategy, it is usually an action under a trade-off situation. So, we think the primate may intake AP and TNC with balance proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-03-12-nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this strategy may be used to balance more nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-03-12-nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-3-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population Monitoring of Gibbons in China</title>
      <link>/publication/2018-03-13-china-gibbon-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018-03-13-china-gibbon-monitoring/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many remnant gibbon populations are left on Hainan?</title>
      <link>/publication/2018-03-13-hainan-gibbon-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018-03-13-hainan-gibbon-survey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the latest demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start guide&lt;/a&gt; or take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of Anthropogenic Threats to Hoolock Gibbon in Yingjiang County in West Yunnan, China</title>
      <link>/publication/2018-03-14-hoolock-gibbon-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018-03-14-hoolock-gibbon-survey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
