<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</title>
    <link>/GuanZH/RBdown/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/GuanZH/RBdown/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>merge two table</title>
      <link>/GuanZH/RBdown/post/merge-two-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/GuanZH/RBdown/post/merge-two-table/</guid>
      <description>summary = “Create a beautifully simple website or blog in under 10 minutes.”
The question is how to merge two tables, it is easy to use merge. However, it is not easy to merge because the two table have different sample sizes and we want to keep all of them.
 Table 1: Some names not in table 2  name plot1    name_a 1  name_y 2  name_q 3  name_n 4  name_m 5  name_v 6  name_p 7  name_d 8  name_i 9  name_g 10  name_c 11  name_k 12  name_f 13  name_j 14  name_e 15     Table 1: Some names not in table 1  name plot2    name_y 1  name_b 2  name_x 3  name_j 4  name_r 5  name_e 6  name_s 7  name_q 8  name_o 9  name_v 10    Now we have problems, some names exist in table 1 but not in table 2, and vice verse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/GuanZH/RBdown/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/GuanZH/RBdown/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>