<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge to graph using same y axis</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</guid>
      <description>In case of that I want to plot several graphs, and the datasets are same and variables are same. How to make it in a compact way, such as I want them share the same y-axis and distinct x-axis, or verse visa. Or I treat X variables in different ways, log and 1/x.
next is the graph using ggplotGrob
Not exactly, but step forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hawking</title>
      <link>/post/rememberinghawking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rememberinghawking/</guid>
      <description> Man’s greatness lies in his power of thought. —— Blaise Pascal
  思想形成人的伟大。人只不过是一根卢伟，是自然界最脆弱的东西；但他是一根会思想的苇草。用不着整个宇宙都拿起武器来才能毁灭他；一口气、一滴水就足以致他死命了。然而，纵使宇宙毁灭了他，人却仍然要比致他于死命的东西更高贵许多；因为他知道自己要死亡，以及宇宙对他所具有的优势，而宇宙对此却是一无所知。 —— 帕斯卡
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step to Student Opening Report</title>
      <link>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</guid>
      <description>Anyway, I still do some student work, including secretary working for opening report defencing. So I use grViz to make a step graph for the procedure.
 {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;diagram&#34;:&#34;\ndigraph boxes_and_circles {\n\n # a \&#34;graph\&#34; statement\n graph [overlap = true, fontsize = 10]\n\n # several \&#34;node\&#34; statements\n node [shape = box,\n fontname = Helvetica, color=OrangeRed]\n a [label = \&#34;Defence Secretary\&#34;];\n b [label = \&#34;Defence Chairman\&#34;];\n c [label = \&#34;Teaching Secretary\&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrients for nonhuman primate</title>
      <link>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</guid>
      <description>Protein is important for primates, because it is the vital source for amino acids.
When we talk about strategy, it is usually an action under a trade-off situation. So, we think the primate may intake AP and TNC with balance proportion.
And this strategy may be used to balance more nutrients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>