<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on LEARNING FROM APES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Score simulation and analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-01-score-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-01-score-analysis/</guid>
      <description> 一次考试成绩能够反应多少东西，分数是否可以反应平时的用功程度，此外还能够反应出什么，采用一个模拟案例分析。
问题1，同学间的成绩差异到底有多大？ 综合汇总同学各科成绩计算总分，总体上属正态分布，最高分与最低分相差超过100分，大部分同学集中于500到560之间，优秀学生占少数，按照80%原则，560以上10人。
问题2，是否存在在成绩上表现极优秀同学？ 从分数上看，没有出现个别极优秀同学，即各门功课均显著突出的。
问题3，同学们的综合成绩表现如何? 综合选择解释力最强的2个主成分分析，能够解释52.2%的成绩差异。如果我主观武断按照7人1组的分群，这5个群体可以在横轴（即主成分1）上区分开来。从图形上看，前1、2、3群个体形成较为密集的分布，而4、5群个体分布较为离散。
问题4，哪些课程影响了同学们的综合成绩？ 观察各门功课对于同学在综合表现上（即对主成分1和2的载荷值）的影响，其中影响最大的3门课是，数学影响最大、其次是化学、然后是英语，这3门课将同学在横轴上拉开。在纵轴上影响最大的3门课，拉开距离的是体育、职业生涯规划、思想道德。虽然相关性分析也反映了总分受到数学、化学和英语影响显著，但实际上这3门课对于总成绩差异的解释很有限，PC1为30.1%。
问题5，这个班级有什么特点？ 1 大多数同学的成绩分数较为集中，成绩最优异的几个同学相对于大部分同学的分数有差距，但并没有非常大的差距，同时没有非常偏科的同学； 2 这个班级大多数同学主要在横轴上有所区分，即数学、化学和英语对于这个班级同学的成绩差异具有显著影响； 3 成绩靠后的同学在纵轴上差异较大； 4 成绩和同学在其他方面上的表现并不明显，在所有同学中，从最左边到最右边，均有个体同学在其他方面的优秀表现没有反映到成绩上； 5 我们无法评价具体分数能够反应出多少同学的能力差异，例如无法评价相差10分能够反映出多少用功程度，但是确定的是相差100分肯定和平时付出的努力相关的，好在该班级在巨大的分数差异上仅有个别同学。
数据虽为模拟，但依然可以表现出PCA的能力，至少一半的个体差异能够表现出来，并能够进行解释；同时，本案例分析受到了一些限制，例如模拟时期较短，科目成绩不全面，且没有考虑到个体本身的能力差异，廖为一窥而已。 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short explanation of graph by PCA</title>
      <link>/post/short-explanation-of-graph-by-pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/short-explanation-of-graph-by-pca/</guid>
      <description>一般来说，PCA分析2个图够了，以iris数据为例，在经过PCA分析后，我们可以得到第一章碎石图，表示PC1，2，3，4的特征向量值，可以据此选择保留的主成分（通常选择特征向量值超过2的变量），此图显示出1个主成分可以保留。
此外，可以有另外2个基于特征向量值选择主成分的标准，即 Kaiser-Guttman 标准和 Broken Stick 标准，这些标准可以反应主成分对于解释原始数据的贡献程度
依据Kaiser-Guttman 标准，仅应该保留主成分1，上图中仅PC1超过了平均值，下图中仅PC1超过了红色柱形图。
在选择了PC后，需要考虑变量对于PC的贡献，下图中，Petal Length，Width， Sepal Length对于PC1的贡献大，即方向偏向x轴方向；而Sepal width对PC2的贡献大，方向偏向y轴。长度越长，相对影响越大。
附简易代码
 head(iris) ir.pca &amp;lt;- prcomp(iris[,1:4], center=TRUE, scale. = TRUE) summary(ir.pca) loadings &amp;lt;- ir.pca$rotation scores &amp;lt;- ir.pca$x plot(ir.pca, type = &amp;quot;l&amp;quot;,main=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;) ev &amp;lt;- ir.pca$sdev^2 source (&#39;http://www.davidzeleny.net/anadatr/doku.php/en:numecolr:evplot?do=export_code&amp;amp;codeblock=1&#39;) evplot(ev) library(&amp;quot;ggbiplot&amp;quot;) ggbiplot(ir.pca, choices=c(1,2), obs.scale = 1, var.scale = 1) ggbiplot(ir.pca,choices=c(1,2), groups=iris[,5], obs.scale = 1, var.scale = 1, ellipse = TRUE)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>奥卡姆剃刀 -- Occam&#39;s Razor, Ockham&#39;s Razor</title>
      <link>/post/occam-s-razor-ockham-s-razor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/occam-s-razor-ockham-s-razor/</guid>
      <description>奥卡姆剃刀（Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor, Ockham&amp;rsquo;s Razor），又称“奥坎的剃刀”，拉丁文为lex parsimoniae，意思是简约之法则，是由14世纪逻辑学家、圣方济各会修士奥卡姆的威廉（William of Occam，约1287年至1347年，奥卡姆（Ockham）位于英格兰的萨里郡）提出的一个解决问题的法则，他在《箴言书注》2卷15题说“切勿浪费较多东西，去做‘用较少的东西，同样可以做好的事情’。”换一种说法，如果关于同一个问题有许多种理论，每一种都能作出同样准确的预言，那么应该挑选其中使用假定最少的。尽管越复杂的方法通常能做出越好的预言，但是在不考虑预言能力（即结果大致相同）的情况下，假设越少越好。
理察·斯温伯恩在逻辑学的背景下讨论简单性： ……对于一个现象的最简单解释，比其他解释更有可能为真，它作出的预言比其他的假设更可能实现，这是认识论的先验首要法则：简单是真理的明证。 ——Swinburne 1997
 奥卡姆剃刀多用于简约统计过程中的复杂程度。奥卡姆剃刀常用于两种假说的取舍上：如果对于同一现象有两种不同的假说，我们应该采取比较简单的那一种。学术研究中普遍希望使用奥卡姆剃刀来降低统计推断的复杂性，以支持某些假设观点。但在使用过程中，需要注意的是，奥卡姆剃刀适用于具有同等解释力的模型（也就是说，它只是告诉我们在同样好的模型中选择较简单的那一个）。奥卡姆剃刀的一个更通用的形式，可以从贝叶斯模型比较中产生。它基于贝叶斯因子，可以适用于那些并不和观察结果同样吻合的模型比较。这些模型有时候可以在解释力和复杂性中找到最好的平衡。总的来说，贝叶斯因子的准确值很难得到，但是有很多种方法给出近似值，例如赤池信息量准则、贝叶斯信息准则、变分贝叶斯方法、错误发现率以及拉普拉斯方法。许多人工智能研究者将这些方法用于奥卡姆学习中。
参考资料:https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A5%A5%E5%8D%A1%E5%A7%86%E5%89%83%E5%88%80</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>assignment work</title>
      <link>/post/assignment-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/assignment-work/</guid>
      <description>I get a work to do. Leader ask me to assign 22 manuscripts to 11 reviewers, guaranting two principles. First, the manuscript can not be assigned to the reviewers who participate in the work. Secondly, the manuscript have to be assigned to reviewers who are familiar with the content, or major in the field.
Ok! I do it in step way. I use rand(), rank() and vlookup().
I give the manuscript random number and randomly sample from them without repeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good data visualization</title>
      <link>/post/good-data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/good-data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Whether data visualization is good depend on the aims of plotting. Usually one people plot for two reasons, or for two purposes. One is exploratory and the other is explanation. For exploratory, one good plot help to creat connection among different subjects, help to broad mind on the research work. For explanation, good plot reveal and explain our results. In most cases, we plot for both reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scraping data from wiki to analyze olympic medal</title>
      <link>/post/scraping-data-from-wiki-to-analyze-olympic-medal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scraping-data-from-wiki-to-analyze-olympic-medal/</guid>
      <description>Today I learn Edwin Thoen from R-blogger. The topic is how to scrape the data from wikepedia and tidy the data in a format in which they can be analyzed. Thank Edwin for sharing the code.
 scrape data from website  I use rvest and tidy package.
library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;) library(tidyverse) library(stringr) Olympics_2018_wiki &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_2018_Winter_Olympics_medal_winners&amp;quot;) sports &amp;lt;- html_nodes(Olympics_2018_wiki, &amp;quot;h2&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% html_text() sports %&amp;gt;% head(3) ## [1] &amp;quot;Alpine skiing[edit]&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Biathlon[edit]&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Bobsleigh[edit]&amp;quot; html_text is used to convert the xml nodes to regular R characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I want to tell about my research</title>
      <link>/post/what-i-want-to-tell-about-my-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/what-i-want-to-tell-about-my-research/</guid>
      <description>About primates, what do I want to tell the others?
It is about biodiversity, evolution, and human beings.
To me, the gibbon is only one of the five hundreds of primate species, and the primates are only five hundreds of the ten millions of animal species.
In Yunnan, most primates dwelled on forests. So all the stories can not happen without refering to forests. In case of we seeing a monkey or gibbon move in tree canopy, we want to know where they are going and what they are going to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to merge to graph using same y axis</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-merge-to-graph-using-same-y-axis/</guid>
      <description>In case of that I want to plot several graphs, and the datasets are same and variables are same. How to make it in a compact way, such as I want them share the same y-axis and distinct x-axis, or verse visa. Or I treat X variables in different ways, log and 1/x.
I use code from stackexchange.com
library(&amp;quot;PtProcess&amp;quot;) lambda &amp;lt;- 1.5 a &amp;lt;- 1 pareto &amp;lt;- rpareto(1000,lambda=lambda,a=a) x_pareto &amp;lt;- seq(from=min(pareto),to=max(pareto),length=1000) y_pareto &amp;lt;- 1-ppareto(x_pareto,lambda,a) df1 &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hawking</title>
      <link>/post/rememberinghawking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rememberinghawking/</guid>
      <description>  Man’s greatness lies in his power of thought. —— Blaise Pascal
  思想形成人的伟大。人只不过是一根卢伟，是自然界最脆弱的东西；但他是一根会思想的苇草。用不着整个宇宙都拿起武器来才能毁灭他；一口气、一滴水就足以致他死命了。然而，纵使宇宙毁灭了他，人却仍然要比致他于死命的东西更高贵许多；因为他知道自己要死亡，以及宇宙对他所具有的优势，而宇宙对此却是一无所知。 —— 帕斯卡
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step to Student Opening Report</title>
      <link>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/step-to-student-opening-report/</guid>
      <description>Anyway, I do some student work, including secretary working for opening report defencing. So I use grViz to make a step graph for the procedure.
 {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;diagram&#34;:&#34;\ndigraph boxes_and_circles {\n\n # a \&#34;graph\&#34; statement\n graph [overlap = true, fontsize = 10]\n\n # several \&#34;node\&#34; statements\n node [shape = box,\n fontname = Helvetica, color=OrangeRed]\n a [label = \&#34;Defence Secretary\&#34;];\n b [label = \&#34;Defence Chairman\&#34;];\n c [label = \&#34;Teaching Secretary\&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrients for nonhuman primate</title>
      <link>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nutrients-for-nonhuman-primate/</guid>
      <description>Protein is important for primates, because it is the vital source for amino acids.
When we talk about strategy, it is usually an action under a trade-off situation. So, we think the primate may intake AP and TNC with balance proportion.
And this strategy may be used to balance more nutrients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>